Hi, Neil. How are you doing?
I'm very well. Thank you, Georgie. How are you?
I'm very well too.
Neil, in this episode of Real Easy English,
we're talking about complaining.
That is when you say something is wrong
or you have a problem and you want to tell someone about it.
Yes, and people should remember that they can get
a free worksheet for this podcast at bbclearningenglish.com.
I know that you have a recent experience with this, don't you?
Ah, yes. Yeah. I booked somewhere to stay on a trip
and the reviews were all really good.
And then when I checked again, the reviews were all really bad.
Oh, no. What were they about?
They said the place was dirty and things were broken.
Oh, no. What did you do? Have you been yet?
Not yet. Oh. No.
So what did you do?
I wrote to them. I sent them an email to say, I was worried.
And I asked them to assure me that the place would be clean
and working properly.
OK. And did you get a response?
I did. But I really hated the whole process.
Oh, no. Why?
Because I don't like complaining.
No, neither do I. I'm not very good at it.
I don't like to make people feel bad, even if there is a problem
and I've paid for something, and it should be a certain way,
but it's not.
And I'm entitled to complain.
I still don't like it.
I just feel, yeah, I feel embarrassed about it.
Yeah. It's not an easy thing to do.
No. I think I'm getting better with age, I think.
I'm getting braver.
I had an experience a couple of weeks ago because I am subscribed
to a food delivery service.
I get a box of food every week.
And the last two weeks, the delivery has been very late.
And I'm not happy about it.
And so I found the courage, found the bravery to call up the customer
service and complain.
And I was very strong and I asked for money, a discount on the next order.
Wow. That sounds very well done.
I think when you do complain, sometimes you feel bad about it.
But if it works out well, like with you, and hopefully with my accommodation,
afterwards you feel really good because you did what was right.
Yeah. If you've paid for something, I think you can expect it to be what you
paid for. So if it isn't, I think you're allowed to complain.
But there is a nice way to do it, isn't there?
There is. Yeah. Be polite. Don't be personal.
It's not often the person you are complaining to is often not the person
responsible for the mistake or whatever.
Yeah. So I think if you are respectful and polite,
but you know what you want.
So Neil, you and I find complaining quite stressful.
So we don't do it very often. But do you know anyone that complains all the time?
Oh, yeah. Some people seem to love complaining and they complain about things
that I would not complain about.
Yeah. I've been in restaurants with groups of people where there's been someone
that has complained about something that is really embarrassing.
And you just think this is not a real big issue.
Has that ever happened to you?
Yeah. The same thing. I've been having a meal with some friends.
One of the people I was with, he used to be a waiter.
And he had a very clear idea about how waiters should behave.
And he didn't like something and he complained about it.
And nobody else really understood what he was talking about or why he was complaining.
And it was embarrassing.
Did he complain to the waiter? Yeah. But so everyone could hear.
Oh, no. And how did the waiter respond?
I don't think he liked it very much.
Well, I used to work in restaurants.
I've also worked in customer service. But in restaurants,
if people have a reason to complain, of course, I'm going to try to fix it.
But it also depends how they say it.
If they're very rude, as a waitress, you don't really want to help them.
But if they're polite and they have a reason to complain, of course,
I'll try to fix their problems.
Okay, Neil, it's time to recap the vocabulary we used in this conversation.
We used the verb complain, which is when you say something is wrong or not good enough.
And we also heard the noun complaint.
We did. And you make a complaint, don't you?
Yes. We also heard discount, which is when you don't pay the full price of something.
You also said that people are entitled to something,
and it means that that is something they should get if they paid for it.
And Neil, you said you were worried about the reviews of the accommodation for your trip,
which is when people write what they think about the place.
That's it then, Georgie. Isn't it?
But join us again another time for more Real Easy English.
Don't forget there's a free worksheet on the website. Goodbye for now.
Goodbye.